# Colby M. White

Texas, United States http://sustainabledev.io colby.white@sustainabledev.io

## **Overview**

Detail-oriented polyglot engineer striving toward using six years of experience to produce sustainable code that does not take significant effort to maintain. Looking to help a remote-first team create well-tested code that enables it to achieve long-term plans. Seeking opportunities that value getting the job done right with as little debt as possible.

# **Technologies**

- · Worked on several RESTful back-end applications across a multitude of frameworks, including Ruby on Rails, Java's JAX-RS, and Python's Django
- Familiar with navigating promise chains and writing application using Node.js
- Written front-end code for various web apps using different JavaScript frameworks, including Angular, Ext.js, and requirejs
- · Familiar with solving problems in multiple style of architectures, including SaaS, microservice, and serverless environments
- Created multiple continuous integration and continuous deployment systems from scratch via tools such as Jenkins, Bamboo, and Codeship
- Coordinated build process for various projects using an assortment languages and frameworks such as Ant, Gradle, Rake, and Maven
- · Deployed applications to various types of environments using tools such as Docker, Chef, and CloudFormation
- Familiar with scripting in different languages, including Ruby, Python, Groovy, and Bash

# **Experience**

#### **Whole Foods Market**

#### **Austin, Texas**

Collaborator

**Open Austin** 

**Austin, Texas** July 2016 - present

DevOps Contractor

May 2016 - present

- Steered efforts to move DevOps team to an automated workflow in order to increase the frequency of code deployments
- Helped research and implement moving the team's technology stack toward a Chef-based and infrastructure-as-code philosophy
- Helped the rollout and deployments of company's new 365 By Whole Foods website, providing operations support to product when required
- · Worked with the official Austin brigade for Code for America to help complete projects
- Led project to compile police bookings in Harris County into an easily searchable database format
- · Provided feedback and input for group projects

#### **Spanning Backup by EMC**

Senior Software Engineer

- Contributed features as a senior member of the development team
- Built out infrastructure for Node. js system tests to enable automated testing of product features that interact with multiple third-party services and APIs

#### **Austin, Texas**

Sept. 2015 - May 2016

- for company's Google Apps Backup product
- Diagnosed and corrected UI performance issues in order to scale the product for large, enterprise customers
- · Created reusable chef recipes for a developer-focused Vagrant machine to help encourage and enforce similarities between team's multiple environments

#### **CA Technologies**

Software Engineer

- · Led team in porting existing enterprise applications to company's custom SaaS platform offering
- · Worked as part of a team tasked with releasing near-greenfield security product to market
- Developed infrastructure and libraries for UI integration testing on the SaaS platform
- Facilitated workflow between designers and developers across several teams in order to turn UI designs into code efficiently
- Coordinated REST-driven interaction among various dynamically scaled components
- · Created custom tool to ease the development and application of

**Austin, Texas** Mar. 2014 - Sept. 2015

- database migrations across environments
- Created localized VM environments to encourage rapid, iterative development and adoption across teams
- · Worked with multiple teams in the company to promote and establish proper testing strategies
- Spearheaded efforts to standardize continuous integration of applications using the SaaS platform via Jenkins
- Built several custom Gradle and Rake plugins to help developer teams quickly deploy applications
- · Created Rake-based build scripts to assemble security product that used multiple languages and frameworks

# Experience (continued)

Allure Energy Austin, Texas

Software Developer

Nov. 2010 - Mar. 2014

- Led team in creating back-end for company's EverSense product, a Wi-Fi touchscreen thermostat with proximity control and an honoree for the 2014 CES Innovations Award
- Implemented DBus-powered messaging schema for sending commands between front-end and back-end code
- Created XMPP messaging schemas to facilitate communication between thermostat and mobile devices
- Used OSGI platform for deployment of Java software to allow for dynamic removal and inclusion of different modules
- Built HTTP-based APIs to facilitate the coordination and communication between multiple devices in order to sync data ranging from registration to weather forecasts

- Created company's policies and procedures on using Ant to package and deploy software
- Worked closely with design team to transition animated screens from concept art to functioning code
- Created an infrastructure from scratch for GUI to allow both users and remote clients to navigate through screens
- Built in-house libraries for common GUI elements in order to promote consistency among screen designs
- Developed design team's concepts for an admin web UI used for monitoring deployed units
- Helped overhaul company's website adding dynamic press releases and a store front to a previously static site

### **Education**

#### **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

University of Texas at Austin May 2012

#### **Bachelor of Journalism**

University of Texas at Austin Aug. 2010

Information valid as of Sept. 2016